<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sean Helvey</title>
    <description>My first word was cheese
</description>
    <link>http://seanhelvey.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://seanhelvey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:58:57 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:58:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calling All Landlocked Surfers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years I’ve been blessed with amazing surfing experiences. I’ve ridden waves from Spain to Hawaii, Mexico, and home in California. As I have gotten older though, many of my friends have stopped surfing for various reasons (work, family, injuries, etc.). Living in Colorado has changed the dynamic quite a bit too. I need to make more of an effort to organize surf travel with friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2017/Landlocked.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EC2 Instances&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2017/Landlocked.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Are you a landlocked surfer?
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a call to all landlocked surfers and those in need of adventure. We might be friends, friends of friends, or future friends. We might not even really like each other. Let’s come together and organize a few surf trips! I’m happy to meet random people along the way, but I know there are plenty of people in my extended network that are jonesin for surf travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2017/encino.gif&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EC2 Instances&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2017/encino.gif&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    If you&#39;re edged &#39;cause I&#39;m weazin all your grindage, just chill.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please share this and help me spread the word. If you know a lonely surfer like me who wants to spend a week somewhere shredding the gnar, I’d love an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/calling-all-landlocked-surfers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/calling-all-landlocked-surfers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Reasons Interest Rates Are Rising</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/mr_toads_wild_ride_pin005.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wild Ride&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/mr_toads_wild_ride_pin005.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Money in the bank or under the mattress, it turns out, may not be that safe after all.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Toad’s Wild Ride is one of the few remaining original attractions at Disneyland Park. It is a wild adventure full of mayhem and havoc. Heading into this new era of economic policy feels like one of the ride’s hallmark hairpin turns. Unpredictable policy, deficit spending, and reduced foreign demand for treasuries are causing interest rates to increase. An increase in borrowing costs and a higher return on cash will prolong the rise in interest rates by slowing the economy and reducing income tax revenue. A quick tour of Mr. Trump’s Wild Ride leads me to the conclusion that interest rates are rising because of these five simple reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unpredictable-policy&quot;&gt;Unpredictable policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty in the markets takes the form of volatility, which has a negative correlation with asset prices. Given the inverse relationship between interest rates and price, an increase in volatility will coincide with an increase in interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deficit-spending&quot;&gt;Deficit spending&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say hypothetically that an increase in military spending will be offset by recuded healthcare expenditures. Still, the increased infrastructure spending will have to come from somewhere. This will likely be funded with debt. An increase in the supply of debt reduces the price, which leads to an increase in interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reduced-foreign-demand-for-treasuries&quot;&gt;Reduced foreign demand for treasuries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We own most of our own debt through the social security trust fund and federal reserve, so renegotating US debt would not fix anything. Our largest international creditors, China and Japan, have other options. They will continue to reduce their demand for treasures as US credit worthiness deteriorates. Reduced demand leads to lower prices and higher interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increased-borrowing-costs&quot;&gt;Increased borrowing costs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As interest rates on government debt increase, so will interest rates on corporate bonds. Both residential and commercial mortgage rates will increase as well. Purchasing assets becomes more difficult as borrowing costs increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;higher-returns-on-cash&quot;&gt;Higher returns on cash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the period of near-zero interest rates comes to an end, the incentive to save money and earn high interest rates will return. While higher returns on cash may seem like a good thing, it comes at the cost of reduced investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased volatility, greater supply, and lower demand for treasuries are causing interest rates to increase. An increase in borrowing costs and a higher return on cash will perpetuate the rise in interest rates by slowing down economic growth and lowering income tax revenue. What is an investor to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current economic outlook presents us with a conundrum. While banks may benefit from higher interest rates, weak economic growth will offset that to some degree. Whether or not the US actually defaults on its debt, we will certainly see panics and crashes over the next couple of years. Ratings agency downgrades, bank-runs, and capital controls combined with the factors outlined above will make it difficult for people to trust banks and take advantage of higher interest rates, while money under the mattress could lose value due to currency depreciation and associated inflationary pressures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal reccomendation would be to purchase high quality stocks when market prices drop. This approach will provide you with a stable stream of growing dividend payments. You can subscribe to my newsletter &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.valunicorn.me/&quot;&gt;Valunicorn&lt;/a&gt; for free during 2016 and remain grandfathered in for life! Whatever you decide, be prepared for a period of rising interest rates due to the five simple reasons outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/5-reasons-interest-rates-are-rising/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/5-reasons-interest-rates-are-rising/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to EC2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Launching and connecting to an Amazon EC2 instance is surprisingly confusing. I ran into a few gaps working through this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ybrikman.com/writing/2015/11/11/running-docker-aws-ground-up/&quot;&gt;Docker tutorial&lt;/a&gt; that I wanted to share. This section explains how to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ybrikman.com/writing/2015/11/11/running-docker-aws-ground-up/#launching-an-ec2-instance&quot;&gt;launch an instance&lt;/a&gt; fairly well, but you may encounter a couple of gotchas before you are able to connect using SSH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/blankDNSIP.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EC2 Instances&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/blankDNSIP.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Are your Public DNS and Public IP fields blank?
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably used the VPC Wizard if this is your first Amazon EC2 instance. If that is the case and your Public DNS is blank, use the “Services” dropdown to navigate over to your VPC. Right click on the VPC ID that is associated with your instance and set the DNS resolution and DNS hostnames to “yes”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/DNSResolution.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EC2 Instances&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/DNSResolution.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Edit the DNS Resolution
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now head over to your Subnet using the navigation menu on the left and use the Subnet Actions dropdown to “Modify Auto-Assign Public IP” so that it is set to “yes”. Unfortuntely you will need to launch a new instance now in order for these two changes to take effect. Your newly launched instance will have beautifully populated Public DNS and Public IP fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;sean-blog-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/PublicIP.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EC2 Instances&quot; class=&quot; lazyloaded&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2016/11/PublicIP.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Auto-Assign Public IP
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only remaining gotcha has to do with your Routes Tables and Internet Gateways, but it is well documented in this trouble shooting guide provided by Amazon: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/knowledge-center/ec2-linux-ssh-troubleshooting/&quot;&gt;How do I troubleshoot problems connecting to my EC2 Linux instance using SSH?&lt;/a&gt; Once you have completed those steps, you should be able to connect to your shiny new EC2 instance!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/how-to-ec2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/how-to-ec2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Life Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly 3 years of consulting, I am excited to announce that I have accepted a full-time job with Pearson! The assessments group here in Boulder does a ton of interesting machine learning and natural language processing, so this is going to be a tremendous learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also been taking a Scala class and learning Elm over the last several months. Huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://degoes.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;John DeGoes&lt;/a&gt; for generously donating his time and everyone in the Elm community for helping me get up to speed. I gained some exposure to classical functional languages and lambda calculus in grad school, but have done basic web development with dynamically typed scripting languages since graduating in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does all of this mean? Expect a flurry of blog posts about things that I don’t understand very well! These aren’t going to be super useful if the topic is in an area where you have expertise. They may be helpful for others who happen to be at the same level. Most importantly though, I want to get back in the habit of writing as I learn. Thanks in advance for understanding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/life-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/life-update/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 12:46:27 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Impact Hub Berlin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that Impact Hub Berlin never changes. Members will come and go, superficial improvements may happen over time, but the warm and colorful community there can withstand all of it. To understand this co-working space, you have to know &lt;a href=&quot;https://zurich.impacthub.ch/impact-hub-berlin/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;its history&lt;/a&gt; and the people behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1180&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/10/image-801041-breitwandaufmacher-gtpu.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1180&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/10/image-801041-breitwandaufmacher-gtpu-300x112.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Managing Director Nele Kapretz with Angela Merkel &quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;112&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/10/image-801041-breitwandaufmacher-gtpu-300x112.jpg 300w, /assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/10/image-801041-breitwandaufmacher-gtpu.jpg 860w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Managing Director Nele Kapretz with Angela Merkel
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One prior endeavor to form Impact Hub Berlin failed. A different group within the community rallied and made another attempt at a prototype, but it still wasn’t clear that the organization would be sustainable. Finally, the effort was successful, and the people here have the space that they always wanted. Take a look at some of the pictures from the renovation below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This space was designed by members Margit Sichrovsky and Kim le Roux of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lxsy.de/&quot;&gt;http://www.lxsy.de/&lt;/a&gt;. They are creating some incredible social funding opportunities in South Africa with their work in Gap Housing. The pair has also made their mark on Impact Hub Berlin in a number of unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “focus area” has an incredible little nook and another section for taking naps! The cafe has a secret spot above the kitchen which can only be accessed with a ladder. The phone booth is unique from every one that I’ve ever seen as is the teams’s commitment to updating and improving the space. The signage out front was being replaced during my week there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1139&quot; style=&quot;width: 235px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2882_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1139 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2882_1024-225x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Member Host Matt Beer&quot; width=&quot;225&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2882_1024-225x300.jpg 225w, /assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2882_1024.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Member Host Matt Beer
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away by the friendly hosts and team members from Impact Hub Berlin. Isabel, Nicole, Steph, and Jonas made me feel right at home. Matt took me out for a traditional German lunch with some awesome Hub Global folks. Vishal Jodhani is the most extraordinary community catalyst and connector that I have ever met! These people are simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure to meet Benjamin Snow of &lt;a href=&quot;https://berlin.impacthub.net/2015/09/30/member-stories-meet-civocracy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Civocracy.org&lt;/a&gt;, who also hails from Colorado. Brock LeMieux made an attempt at starting Impact Hub Oslo before finding his place here in Berlin, but I am hoping he comes back to Boulder at some point, as he has also spent some time in Colorado. Anula and Alexandra gave me an interesting local perspective along with some fantastic book recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is dedicated to all of the people who have started or participated in the creation of an Impact Hub around the world, even those who have failed along the way, and anyone who would consider themselves a member of the community. These places don’t exist in a vacuum. Individuals dream about creating them, but they build teams to make it happen, and work together with many different parties throughout the process (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://zurich.impacthub.ch/impact-hub-manila/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“What does it take to open an Impact Hub?”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for allowing me to visit and tell this story! My hope is that these posts inspire people to become members and tempt existing members into visiting other locations. I’m absolutely inspired after seeing all of it and I’m sure that you will be too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 02:14:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-berlin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-berlin/</guid>
        
        <category>Berlin</category>
        
        <category>Entrepreneurship</category>
        
        <category>Impact</category>
        
        <category>Social</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>Community</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Impact Hub Praha</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was impossible for me to take pictures when I first arrived in Praha (Prague). Everything was so magnificent and cohesive, that capturing any little part of it wasn’t going to do the city justice. This is a incredibly beautiful place. However, it is the people here that make it special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working at Impact Hub Praha gave me a glimpse into the heart of Czech culture. Tomas Surovcik and Jan Říha took me out to lunch, gave me advice on things to do, and helped me find a cheap bus to Munich at the end of my stay. Hosts Danka Nováková and Peter Šedivý were extremely friendly and helpful. I was also able to re-connect with Impact Hub Praha member Felix Palmer who I had met at Nordic.js in Stockholm the prior week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away by the sheer size of the co-working area. It’s very large relative to other Impact Hubs I have been to, and I was told that this is the second largest in the world! The space was literally humming with energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-from-sean&quot;&gt;Tips from Sean&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone speaks English, but why not learn some Czech? Smile and say “děkuji” instead of thank you. Locals will appreciate the effort! Hello is “ahoj” (pronounced “ahoy” like a sailor).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/ncr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.google.com/ncr&lt;/a&gt; is a nice way to prevent google from redirecting your searches according to your geolocation. It will give you the same one from home in the language that you are used to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-from-thomas&quot;&gt;Tips from Thomas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healthy food &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.anantasesa.cz/kontakt&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.anantasesa.cz/kontakt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pub with show &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krcmabrabant.cz/kontakt_en.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.krcmabrabant.cz/kontakt_en.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train models / pub &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vytopna.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.vytopna.cz/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tap your own beer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thepub.cz/?lng=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.thepub.cz/?lng=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 different types of beer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.praguebeermuseum.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.praguebeermuseum.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beautiful view of the city &lt;a href=&quot;http://towerpark.cz/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://towerpark.cz/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-from-danka&quot;&gt;Tips from Danka&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Czech cuisine you must try &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.ufleku.cz/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://en.ufleku.cz/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-can-we-learn-from-impact-hub-praha&quot;&gt;What can we learn from Impact Hub Praha?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three Impact Hubs in the Czech Republic provide members with seamless access across each of the co-working spaces. I’d love to see something like that in the states. They also have a 3D printer and a full bar / kitchen area where people pay for what they use (see the picture of money in the gallery above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the hospitality, Impact Hub Praha! I’ll never forget the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 08:19:02 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-praha/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-praha/</guid>
        
        <category>Impact Hub</category>
        
        <category>Prague</category>
        
        <category>Praha</category>
        
        <category>Social Business</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>Community</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nordic.js</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is unique from other programming languages because it is used not only on the server, but within the browser. So while other languages might give you the ability to create visualizations on the front-end or develop an API on the back-end, JavaScript empowers engineers to do all of those things and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_635&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2367_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-635&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2367_1024-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;We love JavaScript!&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2367_1024-300x225.jpg 300w, http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2367_1024.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    We love JavaScript!
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the incredible variety of topics covered on just the first day at Nordic.js:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are no promises in node.js&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating Expressive UI with ReactJS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgotten Funky Functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bin your select tags&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Augmented reality with JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advanced front-end automation with npm scripts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Through the looking glass – programming on the GPU using WebGL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each one of these talks was extremely impressive. As one of the core contributors to node.js, Bert Belder displayed a deep understanding of the history behind the project along with its implementation details. Tara Jane Feener schooled us on ReactJS, Zeno Rocha blew our minds with his work on augmented reality in the browser, and Felix Palmer put his knowledge of physics to use with his amazing talk on WebGL. My favorite talk of the day was Kate Hudson’s overview of front-end automation with npm scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_638&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2370_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-638&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2370_1024-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The stage&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2370_1024-300x225.jpg 300w, http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2370_1024.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    The stage
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when I thought it couldn’t get any better, Franziska Hinkelmann started day 2 out with an enlightening “trip to the zoo” comparing different JavaScript engines. Her juxtaposition between C++ and JavaScript (below) was a show stopper, as were her tips about avoiding premature optimization and focusing only on the bottlenecks which were truly having an impact on performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_637&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2369_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-637&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2369_1024-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;C++ vs. JavaScript&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2369_1024-300x225.jpg 300w, http://www.bluehook.co/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2369_1024.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    C++ vs. JavaScript
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference was full of interesting people and good vibes. We all had a ton of fun at “Festen” and the techno ping pong party. Getting a ticket wasn’t easy, but it was worth it. Hopefully we will see you all again next year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 06:44:13 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/nordic-js/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/nordic-js/</guid>
        
        <category>augmented reality</category>
        
        <category>Conferences</category>
        
        <category>GPU</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>Mobile Web</category>
        
        <category>node.js</category>
        
        <category>npm</category>
        
        <category>ReactJS</category>
        
        <category>stockholm</category>
        
        <category>Sweden</category>
        
        <category>WebGL</category>
        
        
        <category>Announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Blue Hook is in Europe attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://nordicjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nordic.js&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rejectjs.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reject.js&lt;/a&gt; this month. Along the way I’ll be working out of several Impact Hubs and the whole journey will be documented on &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;my personal blog&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in following along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_623&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-623&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Hook in Stockholm&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024-300x225.jpg 300w, /assets/images/bluehook/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Blue Hook in Stockholm
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 07:51:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/travel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/travel/</guid>
        
        <category>berlin</category>
        
        <category>impact</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>prague</category>
        
        <category>stockholm</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>Announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Impact Hub Stockholm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Travel to a place where you know nobody and instantly become part of the community there. That’s the experience that I had visiting Stockholm and using the Impact Hub Passport! Everyone from the founder to the hosts and members were extremely friendly and collaborative. This has been the first stop on my journey which will take me to 3 (now 4) hubs in Europe, so it will always have a special place in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1017&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1017 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2313_1024&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024-300x225.jpg 300w, /assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2313_1024.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Visiting Hubbers
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The space here is incredible and they have interesting ways of getting members involved with leadership. Their “Community Hosts” volunteer one day per week to earn their membership and they have “Member Hosts” who provide expertise in a particular area such as marketing or IT. They also have &lt;a href=&quot;http://stockholm.impacthub.net/member-clubs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;member lead events&lt;/a&gt; like climbing and running groups each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-makes-impact-hub-stockholm-unique&quot;&gt;What makes Impact Hub Stockholm unique?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Members from Israel, Belgium, France, Germany, Bulgaria, Sweden, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They were open before the first HUB in Islington.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange has actually slept at Impact Hub Stockholm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the trip for me personally was working with Anton Håkansson &amp;amp; Simon Olander Sahlén on their app &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.daycape.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DayCape&lt;/a&gt;, a digital image calendar for children with autism. We hacked on Objective-C together, as they had recently lost their iOS developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;attachment_941&quot; style=&quot;width: 235px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption aligncenter&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2224_1024.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-941 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2224_1024-225x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thumb_IMG_2224_1024&quot; width=&quot;225&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2224_1024-225x300.jpg 225w, /assets/images/seanhelvey/2015/09/thumb_IMG_2224_1024.jpg 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Anton &amp;amp; Simon
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the hospitality everyone! The WineDown was really fun and I had a great time going to the climbing gym with the group. I formed some lifelong friendships during my brief time here in Sweden. I’ll be back, but I hope to see you all in Boulder at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out the fancy adjustable desks. They are awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Members gather every day around noon for lunch. Join them!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t be intimidated by the language. Everyone speaks English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 06:58:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-stockholm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://seanhelvey.com/impact-hub-stockholm/</guid>
        
        <category>Boulder</category>
        
        <category>Colorado</category>
        
        <category>Community</category>
        
        <category>Impact</category>
        
        <category>Stockholm</category>
        
        <category>Sweden</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        
        <category>Community</category>
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
